{"tossups": [{"question": "<em>Barbara Morgan took a leave of absence from work to join this group, although she was only</em> <em>a back-up</em>. A member of this group planned to deliver a 15-minute lecture on \"The Ultimate Field Trip.\" Its leader was Dick Scobee, and their fate was investigated by the Rogers Commission. In honor of this group, the President noted they \"slipped the surly bonds of Earth to touch the face of God.\" This group included New Hampshire teacher Christa McAuliffe, and they died after an O-ring failure early in the launch. For the point, name this group of seven people killed in a space shuttle explosion in 1986.", "answer": "The crew of the <em><b><u>Challenger</u></b></em> [or the <em><b><u>Challenger</u></b></em> expedition; or the <em><b><u>Challenger</u> </b></em>mission; or the crew of the <b><u>OV-099</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>NASA astronauts</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>One of these events was blamed on the British secret service after two MI5 agents were</em> <em>captured in the Venlo Incident.</em> The Kreisau Circle supported one of these actions, and an unimplemented one was dubbed Operation Foxley. One of these actions involved the placing of a bomb in the Wolf's Lair and was to be followed by Operation Valkyrie. That event of this type was the July 20 plot and led to the forced suicide of Erwin Rommel. For the point, name this type of action which sought to overthrow the Nazi regime by killing its leader.", "answer": "<b><u>assassination attempt</u></b>s on Adolf <b><u>Hitle</u></b>r [or obvious equivalents indicating failed <b><u>plot</u></b>s to <b><u>kill</u></b> Adolf <b><u>Hitler</u></b> or failed <b><u>attempt</u></b>s to <b><u>overthrow</u></b> the <b><u>Nazi</u></b> regime; prompt on partial answers]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>This person\u2019s wife was given the desk on which Robert E. Lee signed his surrender in the Civil</em> <em>War</em>. He legendarily amassed a record 726 demerits during his time at West Point. This person was court-martialed for visiting his wife following the failure of the Hancock campaign due to the Kidder massacre. This person won the Battle of Washita River, destroying Black Kettle\u2019s village. His pronouncements of gold in the Black Hills led to a gold rush, and he met his end after leading an attack on a force led by Sitting Bull. For the point, name this American general who died while fighting the Sioux at the Battle of Little Bighorn.", "answer": "George Armstrong <b><u>Custer</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "<em>According to</em> The Economist<em>, this country has produced more foreign fighters in Syria than</em> <em>any other</em>. In November 2014, Beji Caid Essebsi was elected its president, defeating incumbent Moncef Marzouki. In this country, Mohamed Bouazizi\u2019s suicide by self-immolation led to the Jasmine Revolution and the overthrow of Zine (<b>pr. ZEEN</b>) el Abidine Ben Ali. In March 2015, 22 people were killed in a terrorist attack on the Bardo Museum in this country\u2019s capital. For the point, which North African country bordering Algeria and Libya was the starting point of the Arab Spring?", "answer": "<b><u>Tunisia</u></b>n Republic  {II}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "<em>A person of this profession was covertly supplied with gasoline by Andrew Mellon and</em> <em>brought a \"Resolution of the Jobless\" to Congress while leading his namesake \"army\" in 1932.</em> The Program of Social Reconstruction was authored by a man with this job, John A. Ryan. With Francis Townsend, a man with this job founded the Union Party, which ran William Lemke for president. That person with this profession ran the newspaper <em>Social Justice</em> and used his radio show to denounce Jews and the New Deal. For the point, give this profession of Charles Coughlin, who was known as \"Father\" to his followers.", "answer": "Roman Catholic <b><u>priest</u></b>s [or <b><u>father</u></b>s before \"father\" is read; or <b><u>bishop</u></b>s; or <b><u>monsignor</u></b>s; prompt on synonyms like \"clergymen\" or \"ministers\"]  {II}", "metadata": "JB"}, {"question": "<em>This group was alternately named for the founder of the anti-slavery Society of the Friends of</em> <em>the Blacks.</em> This group presented a tripartite \u201cconstitutional project\u201d calling for the abolition of death penalty and the institution of a unicameral legislature. The husband-and-wife team of Jean-Marie and Madame Roland belonged to this group. This group was named after the southwestern department of France where Bordeaux wine is cultivated. They bitterly clashed with a radicalized faction known as The Mountain, or the Montagnards, and their downfall marked the start of the Reign of Terror. For the point, name this moderate faction during the French Revolution.", "answer": "<b><u>Girondist</u></b>s [or <b><u>Girondin</u></b>s; or <b><u>Brissot</u></b>ins]  {II}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "<em>The Republican candidate in this election was depicted as a steam locomotive called the</em> <em>\"Defeatist Limited.\"</em> During this election, Chuck Jones made the film <em>Hell-Bent for Election</em> to support the winner. In a speech in this election, the winner ridiculed assertions that he had sent a US Navy ship to Alaska to pick up his dog Fala. Democratic leaders insisted on dumping Henry Wallace from the ticket before this election and replacing him with a Missouri Senator. For the point, name this presidential election in which Franklin Roosevelt defeated Thomas Dewey to win his fourth term.", "answer": "United States Presidential election of <b><u>1944</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>Many monuments in this nation feature the Turul bird, a mythical falcon</em>. The largest and most sacred building in this nation is the Catholic Basilica at Esztergom. At the center of this nation\u2019s capital is the Chain Bridge, which united two cities in the late 19th century. This country\u2019s coat of arms features the red-and-white Arpad stripes. A tilted cross sits atop this nation\u2019s Byzantine-style Holy Crown, named for its first Christian king, St. Stephen. For the point, which European nation has a gothic Parliament house on the banks of the Danube in its capital of Budapest?", "answer": "<b><u>Hungary</u></b> [or <b><u>Magyarorszag</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "BA"}, {"question": "<em>This man imposed the \u201cmutual guarantee\u201d tax forcing the elite dynatoi classes to pay the</em> <em>taxes of their poorer neighbors.</em> This man came to power by accusing his uncle of the same name, who had the surname Lekapenos, of sympathizing of Bardas Phokas, and he signed a truce with the Fatimids. Vladimir I agreed to convert to Christianity in exchange for receiving the hand of this man\u2019s sister, Anna, in marriage. After winning the Battle of Kleidion, this man ordered the blinding of 99 of every 100 prisoners of the defeated ethnicity, possibly inspiring his nickname. For the point, give the regnal name of this king who was known as the \u201cBulgar-Slayer.\u201d", "answer": "<b><u>Basil</u></b> the Bulgar-Slayer [or <b><u>Basil</u></b> II]  {II}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "<em>Dominic Mancini\u2019s account described the circumstances around this crime</em>. James Tyrrell confessed to this crime, and evidence found during a renovation over a century later supports his account. One suspect in this crime is the Duke of Buckingham, who was a possible heir to the throne of England. The main suspect in this crime had previously served as Lord Protector before usurping the crown from one of the victims. For the point, which crime involved the disappearance of the two sons of Edward IV, and whose most likely perpetrator was their uncle Richard III?", "answer": "disappearance of the <b><u>Princes in the Tower</u></b> [or King <b><u>Edward V</u></b> and <b><u>Richard, Duke</u></b> <b><u>of York</u></b>] {II}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "<em>This man played himself in the movie</em> Rawhide<em>, where he gives up his job to become a</em> <em>rancher.</em> In a speech, this man said it was \"an honor to have known Jacob Ruppert.\" This man said Miller Huggins was a \"wonderful little fellow\" and Joe McCarthy was \"that smart student of psychology, the best manager in baseball.\"On July 4, 1939, this man told a crowd that in spite of \"the bad break\" he had received, he considered himself \"the luckiest man on the face of the earth.\" For the point, name this New York Yankees first baseman who is the namesake of the disease ALS.", "answer": "Henry Louis \u201cLou\u201d <b><u>Gehrig</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>Mary Renault's many novels set among people of this ethnicity include Fire From Heaven</em> <em>and The King Must Die.</em> A writer of this ethnicity wrote about an invasion in a play in which Atossa awaits news about her son; that playwright of this ethnicity legendarily died after an eagle dropped a tortoise on his head. Another writer of this ethnicity documented lawsuits and the \"Five Ages of Man\" for his brother Perses in <em>Works and Days</em> and described the origin of his countrymen\u2019s gods in <em>Theogony</em>. For the point, name this ancient ethnic group of Aeschylus and Hesiod.", "answer": "Ancient <b><u>Greek</u></b>s [or <b><u>Hellene</u></b>s]", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "<em>Senator James Eastland exposed the fact that this person's father had raped and killed</em> <em>women while in the U.S. Army in Italy</em>. J.W. Milam and Roy Bryant talked about this person in a brazen interview with <em>Look</em> magazine, knowing they were protected by double jeopardy rules. This person, while visiting relatives in a town called Money, made the mistake of speaking \"fresh\" to a female grocery store owner. His mother insisted on an open-coffin funeral to show the world his brutally mutilated corpse. For the point, name this African-American teenager, who was murdered in 1955 in Mississippi.", "answer": "Emmett <b><u>Till</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>On some of this man\u2019s inscriptions, he reversed the order of the phrase \u201cSenatus Populusque</em> <em>Romanus,\u201d to \u201cPopulus Senatusque Romanus\u201d to annoy the Senate.</em> He faced a failed conspiracy by his sister Lucilla, and one of his favorites was the Phrygian (<b>pr. FRIDGE-ee-an</b>) freedman Cleander (<b>pr. klee-AN-der</b>). This person celebrated a triumph after he concluded a peace with tribes on the Danube. He claimed that he was Hercules before ritually re-founding Rome as Romulus after a fire. He was finally killed by the wrestler Narcissus after fighting in the Plebeian games. For the point, name this son and successor of Marcus Aurelius.", "answer": "<b><u>Commodus</u></b> [or Marcus Aurelius <b><u>Commodus</u></b> Antoninus Augustus]  {II}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "<em>This composer wrote a \u201cDance of the Persian Slaves\u201d for an opera that depicts the revolt of</em> <em>furloughed guardsmen.</em> This composer described as \u201cfree from German profundity\u201d a tone poem whose choral version became an intermezzo in <em>Sorochyntsi Fair</em>. The streltsy and Old Believers rise up against Peter the Great in this man\u2019s <em>Khovanschina.</em> His only completed opera ends with the Holy Fool singing \u201cFlow, Flow, Bitter Tears\u201d after the False Dmitry has taken power, and depicts the title tsar during the Time of Troubles. For the point, what Russian composer wrote <em>Night on Bald Mountain</em> and the opera <em>Boris Godunov</em>?", "answer": "Modest <b><u>Mussorgsky</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "<em>In 2013, the college dean of this university resigned after admitting she searched private</em> <em>emails to find a leaker</em>. In 2012, over 120 students here were investigated for cheating on the final exam of a class called \u201cIntroduction to Congress\u201d. A man who dropped out of this university has proposed a class on life from the Big Bang to the present called the \"Big History Project.\" A \"beer summit\" was organized by President Obama after this university\u2019s professor Henry Louis Gates was arrested outside his own home in a 2009 case of racial profiling. For the point, name this Ivy League university once attended by Bill Gates, in Cambridge, Massachusetts.", "answer": "<b><u>Harvard</u></b> University  {II}", "metadata": "BA"}, {"question": "<em>A 2012 study of this commodity by Cambridge historian Mary Beth Day argued that its</em> <em>sudden overexploitation caused the largest city in Southeast Asia to fall by the 17th century.</em> The Yasodara Tataka was one place where this material could be found. Villages in Southeast Asia used storage units called <em>trapeang</em> for this resource. Rectangular contraptions called the East and West Barays held this resource for the city of Angkor, which could also obtain it from the Tonle Sap. For the point, name this resource which the Khmer empire also drew from the Mekong river.", "answer": "fresh <b><u>water</u></b> [or rain <b><u>water</u></b>; or ground<b><u>water</u></b>; or <b><u>H</u><u>2</u><u>O</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>This person was the editor of Larry Gonick's book \u201cThe Cartoon History of the Universe</em>.\u201dThis person said \"We have such a great civilization\" while giving a televised house tour with CBS' Charles Collingwood. In an interview with Theodore White, this person quoted Queen Guinevere in describing her family's love of the musical <em>Camelot</em>. She wears a blood-stained pink suit in a photo taken of her on a plane. This woman married a Greek shipping magnate in 1968, five years after her husband's murder. For the point, name this First Lady married to a President assassinated in 1963.", "answer": "<b><u>Jacqueline Kennedy</u></b> [or <b><u>Jackie Kennedy</u></b>; or Jacqueline \u201cJackie\u201d <b><u>Bouvier</u></b>; or Jacqueline \u201cJackie\u201d <b><u>Onassis</u></b>; prompt on <b><u>Kennedy</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>An early 2000s health crisis in North America among users of this substance resulted from</em> <em>its mixture with levamisole, a downer used by veterinarians.</em> Albert Niemann's 1860 dissertation described all the steps required to synthesize this compound, whose precursor factored into the experiments of Paolo Mantegazza. An 1884 pamphlet by Sigmund Freud popularized this drug's use for the relief of depression in Europe. This triple reuptake inhibitor is an alkaloid refined from a South American plant. For 10 points, name this drug once found legally in a soda rivaling Pepsi, a white powder which can be solidified into \"crack.\"", "answer": "<b><u>cocaine</u></b> [or <b><u>benzoylmethylecgonine</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>The architect Domenico Fontana renovated this city, whose walls were reinforced by the</em> <em>military engineer Giuliano da Sangallo.</em> The anti-Spanish policies of Paul IV incited a Philip II-led invasion of this city. During Charles V\u2019s sack of this city in 1527, Clement VII took refuge in its Castel Sant\u2019Angelo. This city has made a concert venue out of the Baths of Caracalla and a hospital can be found on its Tiber Island. For the point, name this city, the capital of the Papal States before the foundation of its enclave of Vatican City.", "answer": "<b><u>Rome</u></b> [or <b><u>Roma</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "AG"}, {"question": "<em>According to tradition, this man was born after a war elephant knelt and refused to attack</em> <em>the city where he would be born.</em> Tradition holds that this man was commanded <em>\u201ciqra,\u201d</em> meaning \u201crecite,\u201d by a figure who appeared to him yearly. Early helpers of this man are known as <em>ansar.</em> This man banished the Banu Nadir Jews after his defeat at Uhud, which came after his victory at Badr. He later won the Battle of the Trench against his own Quraysh tribe. During his <em>hijra,</em> he went to Medina after fleeing Mecca. For the point, name this prophet and founder of Islam.", "answer": "<b><u>Muhammad</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>A legend in this country concerns the vengeful spirit Black Vaughan, who was finally</em> <em>exorcised by a mother with a newborn baby</em>. The beast of Bodmin was a phantom cat that terrorized much of this country\u2019s bumpkin inhabitants. A king of this country ordered that all children born on May Day be executed, but that didn\u2019t kill his bastard son by Morgause. The Battle of Camlann was fought in this country, and afterwards, one of its kings went to Avalon. For the point, name this modern day country whose folklore includes the Excalibur sword and King Arthur.", "answer": "<b><u>United Kingdom</u></b> of <b><u>Great Britain</u></b> and Northern Ireland [accept either underlined; or <b><u>UK</u></b>; or <b><u>England</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "Ike"}, {"question": "<em>The decision to hold this meeting was agreed to in the Treaty of Chaumont.</em> A key organizer of this event was Friedrich Gentz. At this meeting, Russia agreed to return Galicia to Austria, but gained the newly created Duchy of Warsaw. This gathering also incorporated Belgian lands into the Kingdom of the Netherlands, and organized a loose German Confederation. Delegates at this meeting included the Viscount Castlereagh and Tsar Alexander I himself. For the point, name this 1815 summit hosted by Klemens von Metternich in the Austrian capital.", "answer": "Congress of <b><u>Vienna</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>This city's metropolitan area used the BLISS program to try and solve a public housing</em> <em>shortage in the 1970s and 80s.</em> The fortress of Intramuros was built to protect this city by a conqueror who soon died of heart failure, named Miguel L\u00f3pez de Legazpi. This city is the namesake of a fleet of silver-bearing galleons that travelled between it and Acapulco, Mexico. The Pasig river, which bisects this city, empties into a namesake bay where Charles Gridley was told to \"fire when ready\" on Spanish gunboats in 1898. For the point, name this long-time seat of government of the Philippines.", "answer": "<b><u>Manila</u></b> [or Metropolitan <b><u>Manila</u>] </b> {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>Two of this leader's children with Maria Martinez had names referencing the opera</em> Aida<em>.</em> This leader required churches to post a slogan translated as \"God in Heaven, [this man] on Earth.\"This man's brutal secret police, the SIM, was led by Johnny Abbes, and was responsible for planting a bomb in Romulo Betancourt's car and killing the Mirabal sisters. He was killed when his Chevrolet Bel Air was ambushed outside the capital in 1961. In the Parsley Massacre, this leader's troops killed thousands of neighboring Haitians. For the point, name this man who, in 1937, became dictator of the Dominican Republic.", "answer": "Rafael <b><u>Trujillo</u></b> Molina  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>According to legend, the city of Udine (<b>pr. OO-dee-nay</b>) was founded by this man so that he</em> <em>could watch the siege of Aquileia (<b>pr. ah-quill-AY-uh</b>)</em>. St. Genevieve was canonized after her prayers supposedly stopped this man from attacking Paris. This man forced Theodosius II to pay him tribute, but after he stopped payment, this man defeated him and tripled the tribute. After receiving a letter from Honoria, the sister of Valentinian III, this brother of Bleda was dissuaded from attacking Rome by Pope Leo I. For the point, name this so-called \u201cScourge of God\u201d, a ruler of the Hunnic Empire.", "answer": "<b><u>Attila</u></b> the Hun  {II}", "metadata": "TR"}, {"question": "<em>Comedian Jackie Mason allegedly extended his middle finger on air during an episode of this</em> <em>show</em>. This show's original title was <em>Toast of the Town</em>, and its star became furious after the word \"higher\" was added to the sanitized lyric \"Girl, we couldn\u2019t get much better.\" In an episode of this show, the caption \"Sorry girls, he's married\" was superimposed over a performer. Supposedly, its host wanted to censor Elvis Presley by only filming him from the waist up. For the point, name this long-running variety show whose namesake host welcomed the Beatles in their 1964 debut on American television.", "answer": "<em>The</em> <em><b><u>Ed Sullivan</u></b>Show</em> [accept <em><b><u>Toast of the Town</u></b></em> before mentioned]  {II}", "metadata": "MC"}, {"question": "<em>The attacking side in this battle failed to outflank the defenders, led by Tuchkov, on their</em> <em>right through the forest near the village of Utitsa</em>. The Raevsky redoubt in the center of the lines of the defenders in this battle was captured and recaptured several times. It began with an assault on Bagration\u2019s fleches by General Davout (<b>pr. duh-VOO</b>), and Davout\u2019s commander failed to commit the Imperial Guard in this battle. Barclay de Tolly was removed from command prior to this battle for refusing to give battle. For the point, name this battle fought by General Kutuzov, against Napoleon in Russia.", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Borodino</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "JZ"}, {"question": "<em>European authority over this colonial region was enshrined in the Bond of 1844, which the</em> <em>Fante</em> (<em><b>pr. FAHN-tay</b></em>)<em> people agreed to.</em> The Dutch sold Elmina castle, which processed slaves for centuries, to this colonial region. A siege of Kumasi was carried out by Garnet Wolseley in this region, which witnessed a 1900 desecration of the Golden Stool. For the point, name this site of the Ashanti Wars, a British colonial region which became Ghana after independence.", "answer": "British <b><u>Gold Coast</u></b> [do not accept or prompt on \"Ghana\"]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>One teacher here, Johannes Itten, promoted the Mazdaznan cult.</em> The foundation course at this school was taught by Laszlo Moholy-Nagy (<b>pr. NAHZH</b>), and a museum dedicated to this school can be found in the White City of Tel Aviv. Its second head, Hannes Meyer, was dismissed from the city of Dessau in 1930 due to \u201cCommunist machinations.\u201d It was permanently closed rather than accede to Nazi demands to replace Vassily Kandinsky by its final director, Ludwig Mies van der Rohe. For the point, what Weimar-era Modernist German art school was founded by Walter Gropius?", "answer": "<b><u>Bauhaus</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "CW"}, {"question": "<em>The six assassination attempts against this man included a 1995 attack on his limousine in</em> <em>Addis Ababa</em>. Near the end of his rule, this leader re-created the office of Vice President for his intelligence director Omar Suleiman. While he was in power, this leader of the National Democratic Party, or NDP, faced dissent from a head of the International Atomic Energy Agency named Mohamed ElBaradei, who joined January 2011 protests against this ruler in Tahrir Square. For the point, name this Egyptian dictator who resigned during the Arab Spring.", "answer": "Hosni <b><u>Mubarak</u></b> [or Muhammad Hosni Sayyid <b><u>Mubarak</u></b>]  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>One ruler from this family attempted a land swapping agreement that was opposed by the</em> <em>F\u00fcrstenbund.</em> That ruler from this family was visited by Pope Pius VI after his Edict of Idle Institutions closed monasteries in his realm. Another ruler from this family allied with France and Russia in the Diplomatic Revolution. That ruler from this family took the throne thanks to the 1713 Pragmatic Sanction, which prompted the War of the Austrian Succession. For the point, what ruling family of the Holy Roman Empire included Joseph II and Maria Theresa?", "answer": "<b><u>Habsburg</u></b>s or <b><u>Hapsburg</u></b>s  {II}", "metadata": "SH"}, {"question": "<em>In 1866, French admiral Pierre-Gustave Roze invaded this landform, taking almost 300</em> <em>royal scrolls back which are still in Paris.</em> A mugwort soup is common in the cuisine of this landform, where a mythical bear ate nothing but garlic and mugwort to become a woman. The main language of this landform has an idiosyncratic dialect spoken on Jeju island to its south. Construction halted in 1992 on a triangular, 105-story hotel on this peninsula, where failed invasions ran aground at the Salsu river going south and the Yalu river going north. For the point, name this peninsula whose Han river flows north of the Gangnam district of Seoul.", "answer": "<b><u>Korea</u></b>n peninsula  {II}", "metadata": "MJ"}, {"question": "<em>This man designed a town layout consisting of repeating cells of twelve rectangular blocks</em> <em>each surrounded by a central green square.</em> This man ordered the construction of Fort Frederica, which was unfinished during an invasion that led to his force's victory at the Battle of Bloody Marsh. That attack by the Spanish was in retaliation after he led a failed attempt to capture St. Augustine. This man formed a friendship with the Yamacraw chief Tomochichi. He helped organize a settlement next to the Savannah River. For the point, what man wished to create a safe haven for debtors through the founding of Georgia?", "answer": "James <b><u>Oglethorpe</u></b>  {II}", "metadata": "JL"}, {"question": "<em>In a book about</em> The Myth of<em> this campaign, Angus Calder stated that, contrary to popular</em> <em>depictions, the people it affected were not united.</em> The targets of this campaign took refuge in Morrison shelters. A part of this campaign codenamed Operation Moonlight Sonata destroyed the 14th-century St. Michael's Cathedral and most of the city of Coventry. This campaign's ultimate failure caused its instigator to postpone Operation Sea Lion indefinitely. For the point, name this German bombing campaign against Britain.", "answer": "the <b><u>Blitz</u></b> [accept Battle of <b><u>Britain</u></b> until \"Britain\" is read; do not accept \"Blitzkrieg\"]  {II}  <b>Extra Tossup \u2013 ONLY READ IF A QUESTION IS BOTCHED!</b> <em>After the death of a member of this family, a poem beginning \"Those midnight stars are sadly</em> <em>dimmed\" was written</em>. A member of this family died at age three and was honored with the poem \"Little Eddie.\" Another member of this family had a cleft lip and was given a nickname because of his constant wriggling \u201clike a tadpole.\u201d Children in this family disrupted White House meetings with animals, although one would die of typhoid fever early in his father's presidency. While Tad died young, Robert Todd from this family lived to adulthood. For the point, name this family of the assassinated sixteenth President of the United States.  ANSWER: <b><u>Lincoln</u></b> family  {II}", "metadata": "KG"}], "bonuses": []}